Inventory of the Overseas Weekly photographs
Hoover Institution Archives
- Contact Sheet 12763, circa 1967-1971
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Feb. 3: (1a-4a) Pfc. Paul V. Healey, hero of the Embassy, back on duty two days after the fighting in the first hours of the VC [Viet Cong] attack on Saigon. (5a) Healey holds the Chinese Communist .45 he took off the body of a Viet Cong in the Embassy grounds. (6a-7a) Healey talks on radio of one of the MP jeeps. (8a-10a) Lt. Col. Richard E. George, provost marshal of Saigon. (His picture is for wrap up on MP war which will be in next package). (1) Motor scooter (I don't know why I have a picture of it) (2-7) Company of APCs from the 3d Bn., 4th Cav., 25th Inf. Div. moves down Duy Tan street toward the big Catholic cathedral near the center of the city. The tracks were headed for a trouble spot Cholon. Vietnamese civilians on scooters and in private cars detour around the American soldiers. (8) A sergeant atop one of the tracks watches with interest as a pretty Vietnamese girl tries to pass his APC. (9) A Vietnamese cop makes the girl turn around and take another route around the armored column. (10-15) More shots of the 25th Inf. Div. armored column on Duy Tan street. The column was halted for about 15 minutes in the street. In frames 12 and 13, a sergeant stretches. (16-18) An MP machine gun jeep patrols downtown Saigon. On Tu Do Street a block from the Rex BOQ. (19) Blockades were put up on streets throughout the city. There was a curfew on the civilian population, though many Saigon citizens violated it. US military men and civilians were ordered to stay in their billets until told they could leave. (20-20a) Lt. Col. Gordon D. Rowe, commander of the 716th MP Bn.(for MP war wrap-up to come).
- Contact Sheet 12764, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Buddhist orphanage party - Vietnam children with soldier.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Envelope 9: (12) Thich Nhat Thien, the monk who is director of Buddhist orphanages in Vietnam, asked the children to the show the GIs around the barracks like buildings where the youngsters live. Here two GIs and their young friends struggle with the language barrier and try to make conversation in one of the dormitories. Solders are Pfc. Robert Roemhild (left) and Sp4 Steve Bailey. (13) Bailey with boys on bed. (14) Roemhild with youngster. (15) Bailey with boy. (16-17) …gives a happy boy a ride on his shoulders while a crowd of children follows./Envelope 10: (19) A pensive youngster watches the festivities. (20-21) Sp5 Robert Hale passes out clothing sent from home by the family of a sergeant from his outfit./Envelope 7: (0-2) Boys at orphanage empty GI trailer of cokes in record time. Soldiers of 64th QM Bn. Brought the drinks for the Tet party. (3) Youngster serves a coke to Sp4 Paul Felix, who was among two busloads of troopers who came to Saigon from Long Binh for the party. (4-5) Gis and kids./ Envelope 8: (6-9) Gis and kids. (10-11) Sp4 Clyde Clark kneels to talk to a small boy.
- Contact Sheet 12765, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - MPs in Saigon - patrol outside US embassy.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: (3a-4a) MP dashes from tree to tree down a Saigon street, making his way to a half-finished building across the street from one side of the Independence Palace. In the building, VC [Viet Cong] were exchanging fire with Vietnamese soldiers and police inside the palace grounds. (5a-7a) rear view of the same MP, and the almost deserted street (These pix aren't much, I'm afraid, but I was standing behind a tree.). All are shots of MPs on same street. MP in 12a is an Australian MP sergeant, a tough, calm copy who winked at me when he trotted past my tree. (14a) An MP jeep speeds down a main Saigon street. (15a-17a) A French woman in a bright, flowered minidress stands on a corner, peering down the street toward the Independence Palace where a fire fight was going on. In Frame 17a she talks to a French photographer (wearing shorts). (18a) MPs outside Splendid BOQ keep well covered. They were only two blocks from the fire fight at the Palace and said stray rounds occasionally whistled down the street in their direction. (19a) Another MP jeep. (20a) A roving patrol brings iced tea and chow to a three-man patrol on duty outside the US Embassy the day after the attack on it. (Last frame) Sgt. Alger Sanders, 20, sits at wheel of the jeep on guard outside the Embassy. Sanders was on the scene early Wednesday morning soon after the Embassy was attacked.
- Contact Sheet 12766, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Buddhist orphanage party - Vietnam children with soldiers - 6-10.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: All following pictures were taken at a Tet party for children at the Buddhist Orphanage Center in Saigon. The GIs are from the 64th QM Bn., stationed at Long Binh. (1a-2a) Sp4 Herbert Garner (foreground, in hat) and Sp4 Clyde Clark sit on their heels to join a crowd of small Vietnamese boys at the orphanage party. (3a-8a) Sp4 Garner feeds cookies to his tiny friends at the orphanage. The children's home is located on the compound of the Buddhist headquarters in the city. (10a-11a) Pfc. Joe Rainbolt has his arms full with two little boys. Many of the children in the home are youngsters orphaned by the war or separated from their families by the fighting and upheaval. (12a-15a) Rainbolt accepts a cup of tea, then plays around with youngster who had appropriated his fatigue hat. (16a-18a) GIs play around with youngsters. (19a-end) Pfc. Kenneth McKim with young boy who was enjoying his Coke.
- Contact Sheet 12767, 1968 February 3
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - NCO's - Jackson, Msgt, William - hospital.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Photo captions 3 Feb 68 - undeveloped roll - The last six frames on this are three mug shots and three slightly longer shots of Sgt. Bill Jackson in his office. On the same roll should be a number of photos of the 3d Field hospital patients standing guard. The first of these were taken from my scooter, through the fence and is of Pfc. Gerald Smith. Next are some taken from the inside, first of Smith, then three guards in a row, nearest to the camera is Stockdale, then Smith, then Morgan. The last photos in this series are of Gary ("Hell's Angeles Yacht Club") Oliver.
- Contact Sheet 12768, 1968 February 10
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Army US officers - Maj. Barry Eagan - Maj. Jim Bowen - Col. Ewing - courts and lawyer.
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Aussie court-martial - Maj. Barry Eagan (defense counsel) - Maj. Jim Bowen (prosecuting counsel) - Col. Ewing (Ja Col.).
- Contact Sheet 12769, 1968 February
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - 1st Lt. Fred Gentile - Sp4 Richard Greenwood (glasses) - Army US officers - Vietnam Med. Corps - Pfc. Rickey Britt (medic).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Feb. 12: All taken with D Co., 3d Bn., 7th Inf, 199th Light Inf. Brig. I couldn't keep a frame-by-frame ID. First half of the film contains general shorts of area the troops were searching. They show columns moving down street, burned out houses, the duster track moving down the street. A couple of shots show heap of VC [Viet Cong] bodies mentioned in story. Around the middle of film: Several pictures of medic Pfc Rickey Britt treating and bandaging the injured Vietnamese woman mentioned in story. Following are several shots of 1st Lt. Fred Gentile, 2d platoon leader, breaking open door of house with a pick. A few shots of a GI (no name) and a Vietnamee interpreter going through a Vietnamese Air Force officer's rucksack they found in one of the houses. There are two shots of a GI carrying a toy plastic rifle he liberated from one of the houses. He has on glasses and is Sp4 Richard Greenwood, 20. Then several shots of the duster track turning a very tight corner in the narrow dirt streets. Last pictures are of more Gis breaking open another door.
- Contact Sheet 12770, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Saigon - fighting.
- Contact Sheet 12771, circa 1967-1971
- Contact Sheet 12772, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Nha Trang - fighting & Gia Din.
- Contact Sheet 12773, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Nha Trang fighting.
- Contact Sheet 12774, circa 1967-1971
- Contact Sheet 12775, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Saigon fighting.
- Contact Sheet 12776, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Capt. Frank Marriano - law officer Col. Paul J. Tobin on KP - Ann.
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Capt. Frank Marriano - refugees - Lt. Col. Paul J. Tobin ( law officer ) on KP.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: (2) A military spokesman in Saigon today said… (3) Ann Bryan, famous woman war correspondent and the Elsa Maxwell of RVN. (4-5) Capt. Frank Marriano (6-7) Refugees (8-10) Chopper strike in area of Vo Di Ngui (19-20) Law Officer Col. Paul G. Tobin on KP at Rex Hotel for short story.
- Contact Sheet 12777, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Nha Trang - Captured NVAs [North Vietnamese Army] & weapons - Sgt. Richard Dioguardi (in tiger suit) carrying a live mortar.
- Contact Sheet 12778, 1968 February 9
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Saigon - Sgt. Charles Smith (waiting for a special court) - rice trucks being unloaded - an accident - GI chatting with bar girl - Sp4 Bob Edwards (guarding an alley).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: First two frames will be shots of Sgt. Charles Smith, story to come, who is in Saigon trying to hire a civilian lawyer to defend him at a special court martial. The third and fourth frames will be mug shots of him. The next ten or so frames will include shots of the rice convoy and loading the trucks at the Cholon warehouse, mug shots of S. Sgt. Charles Wine, a shot of a woman tossed from her motor scooter in an accident in which a GI driver was involved (he was certainly driving fast for the heavy traffic near the central market) but to what extent or responsibility, I don't know, and a GI (S. Sgt. Wine but not for ID) chatting with out-of-work bar girls at an open air bar-café. The final three or four shots show war-blasted neighborhood in Gia Dinh, near Saigon River bridge, and "Happy New Year" written in the Chinese-Vietnamese style, but in English. One more I forgot (It's near midnight, my typewriter has been sticking on "h" and "n" and I'm getting punchy) is a GI guarding an alley mouth behind a pile of smoldering garbage. He is Sp4 Bob Edwards, 20, of Bevier, Mo., a HAC bus driver…
- Contact Sheet 12779, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - David Gitelson.
- Contact Sheet 12785, 1968 February
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Refugees - Marines - D Co. 1/5 of the Lst Mar. Div. resting along wall - Marines carry wounded to helipad - jeep with skull.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Feb. 17? Hue photo captions: (1-3) refugees in the park on south bank of Perfume River, some washing clothes in ornamental pool. Knocked out bridge in background, citadel and VC [Viet Cong] side of the river further on. (4-5) 1st Plt., "Delta" Co., 1/5 of the 1st Mar. Div., resting along wall waiting to move across the river for fighting in the citadel. They didn't. Orders changed and they fought on the south perimeter of the town. (6-7) the chopper pad on the waterfront. (8-9) Refugees living in still-incomplete theater on U of Hue campus. (10-11) Marines carry wounded buddy to helipad. (13-15) jeep with skull (story) (16-17) decorated jeep part of improvised motor pool. (18-19) the MacV Compound goose.
- Contact Sheet 13084, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Marine beach Da Nang - O2.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Hue photo captions, Feb. 17? (2-3) "Up Tight, Sir" on army jeep at Force Logistic Command, a Marine base at Red Beach, Da Nang. (4-7) Marine "inserts" ready to move out. Some have faces painted green and black. Pancho Villa-type hat styles. These guys are airlifted into VC [Viet Cong] territory for several days at a time, observe and call artillery and air strikes, then are helilifted out. (8-10) Viet Marines loading up. (11) still don't know the name of this plane. (12) The convoy was stopped for more than an hour-- no one had bothered to check whether an out bridge had been repaired, but it hadn't. (13-14) C-rat cartons add a homey touch to rural Vietnamese architecture. (15-16) the convoy is stalled, but life goes on for the villagers, including (16) an elder in traditional dress riding his bike. (17-20) Scenes along slaughter alley. (21) Hope the Marines were just kidding when they named their tank.
- Contact Sheet 13085, 1968 January 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - recreation (special services camp) - contact sheet - p-1-OWP.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: All pictures taken at Special Services recreation camp just outside Saigon. (2) Troopers from 199th Light Inf. Brig., fresh from the field, brought their own entertainment, including a band, dancing girls and singers. Later they enjoyed steaks and beer at a cookout. (3) GIs from 199th are engrossed watching dancing girls. (5-6) GIs lounge in the sun and under umbrellas. The bar and chow pavilion is on the left. (7) Soldiers relax in the sun and under umbrellas. At right is the Saigon river, where GIs can take boat rides or water ski. (8) Inside of the bar and food pavilion. (9) Several soldiers who brought their own chow use one of the several charcoal pits. (10-11) Soldiers play ping pong on a rain-warped table. In back is the bar and food pavilion. (12-14) Trooper whose shirt indicates he's worried about the world watches the dancing girls. (15-17) The 199th soldier shout approval of the dancing. (18) Two GIs pull away from docks for a boat ride on the river. A Vietnamese boy carries gas for another boat. (20) Trooper reaches high to make a point for his team in volleyball game.
- Contact Sheet 13086, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - man on the street - M-O-S + Ann Bryan - OWP Feb 3.
- Contact Sheet 13087, 1968 February 27
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sp5 Susan Johson.
- Contact Sheet 13089, 1968 February 17
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Hue - Greenspon.
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Hue - action.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Feb. 17, 1968 - Hue sheet "A" (2) looking across the ARVN compound to refugees living in the U of Hue buildings (3) blown bridge across the Perfume river (A Vietnamese girl friend assures me the translation of the name of the river really means "River that Smells," with no reference to whether the smell is pleasing or not) with civilians crossing on a pontoon span. Behind the trees to the rear is the citadel. (4) newsmen walk along Le Loi Street, which runs along the southern bank of the Perfume river. I thought this house was in bad shape, but it turned out to be pretty well preserved. (5) Marine tank passes a Hue Hospital ambulance -- bullet riddled -- in front of the hospital entrance (6-7) two dead VC [Viet Cong] in the park between Le Loi Street and the river (8) these VC were in the yard of the city hall building at Hue. Militia men were still shooting occasionally at VC snipers behind the rear of the building. The attempt to burn the bodies hadn't been too successful so far as their legs and feet were concerned. Building is also province headquarters. (9): the same dead VC as in frame 8. (10) civilian refugees coming down Le Loi street. The trees in the park and yards were all shot to hell, place looked like a hurricane had hit. (11-19) the pig crews. In shot 14, left to right, Chambers' blond head, Matula, Brock and Marsh. It was getting dark and I was shooting by guess. In 17 it's Matula, Brock, Marsh (no mask) and Chambers. (20-21) Shiv? (big) and Kali (little).
- Contact Sheet 13091, 1968 March 3
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Saigon - closed bars.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: These are shot of closed bars in downtown Saigon, except that most of them are still in operation. On the shots of a girl looking out from a bar, please block out her face if you use photo. She is an old buddy and I'd hate to see her get into trouble if this is used. Sure, also, you have plenty of shots of bars in the good old days. maybe: "are these days gone forever?"
- Contact Sheet 13092, 1968 March 30
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - man on the street - Miss Lee (marriage broker).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: (2-3) Emmezieh Thomas (4) James Long (5) Dean Hippe (6) Ronald Bowens (7) Brandston Lacy (8) Ed Jones (9) George Newby (10-13) Miss Lee.
- Contact Sheet 14040, 1967 December 24
  ENVELOPE TEXT: CWO Arthur Walters - S. Sgt. Robert Reynolds - black market - acquittal - Reynolds - Vietnam officers - handwriting expert - contact Sheet C.
- Contact Sheet 14041, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - man on street.
- Contact Sheet 14042, 1967 March 26
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - man on the street - S. Sgt. John J. McGinty (Marines).
- Contact Sheet 14045, 1968 March 2
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Parachutes - air drop at Khe Sanh - high scanned (not clean).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: March 2 - Photos of Khe Sanh by Bob Handy, OW freelancer - All the pictures show Air Force C130s making drops of C rations, ammo and other vital supplies. Airlift is the only means supplying Khe Sanh now and the enemy has virtually closed down the airstrip with huge volumes of anti-aircraft fire. When the weather permits, a few choppers get in. The C130s land occasionally, when the weather and enemy fire permit. If they land, the 130s shove pallets of cargo and people out the huge back door, yank on any passengers who want to get out, and take off again, all literally within seconds. They can be airborne again within a minute or two. They never shut off engines. There's a story going around, which may be apocryphal but illustrates the kind of things that can happen at Khe Sanh. Allegedly an Air Force pilot was deadheading (riding as a check pilot or in some other function but not a member of the crew) on one of the 130s that landed at Khe Sanh. He helped the crew shove out the cargo and then was trying to pull on a passenger. The plane was already starting its take off roll and the man on the ground was heavy. He pulled the pilot out of the plane instead of the pilot pulling him on. The pilot raced back for the 130 and hung onto the back door for about 15 yards but had to turn loose. The plane took off without him and he's allegedly still stuck in Khe Sanh. (This paragraph comes from a story I heard here, not from Handy). 1st Lt Bryan Traynor has the job of getting the pallates of ammo and C rats from the drop zone, which is outside the perimeter at Khe Sanh, down to the various units and supply depots inside the base. It's a hairy job since it has to be done under the almost constant heavy artillery fire raining on Khe Sanh base. (Unfortunately, there's no picture of Traynor here). There are an average of 10 airdrops a day at Khe Sanh. (1-2) Show cargo chutes dropping out of tail of 130 over Khe Sanh. (6-7) Show 130 landing in the battered Khe Sanh base. (3) Cargo chutes land in perimeter wire. They set off a trip flare--a dangerous situation since the three pallets had 105 ammo on them. (4-5) Cargo pallettes kick up dust as they land. These also are pallettes which set off flare. Quote from Handy in his note from Khe Sanh: "I hope this is enough information. I could have managed more facts and figures but due to the goddamn steady incoming it's pretty hard to move about." Handy is inexperienced but sometimes comes up with good pictures. He intended this as a photo story but it's not. Think you could be able to get a couple of wild photos out of them. Ann.
- Contact Sheet 14046, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Melvin Belli - Col. Robert H. Ivey - Danny Jones - Army US officers - contact sheet A.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Belli caption - Phil Jordan - Sheet "A" - (2) Belli (white hair, black-rimmed glasses) at Rex Hotel officers mess, Saturday, Jan. 20, before luncheon hosted by Federal Bar Association members in Saigon. Belli needs a shave, had arrived late that same morning. Only other ident in this frame is Col Robert H. Ivey, MacV SJA, who is standing behind B's left elbow (and wearing khaki's). Danny Jones of Los Angeles, B's law partner and companion on this trip (more or less his Boswell) is obscured by Belli. (3) Ditto and you can see Jones a little better apparently picking his teeth. (4) ditto, with good view of Jones, to B's right. (8-11) Belli speaking after luncheon.
- Contact Sheet 14047, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Melvin Belli (B) - Danny Jones - Lt. Col. Jack Dixon - Lt. Col. James A. Theros - Bearcat pool - Vietnam US officers.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Sheet "B" (also Bearcat pool story) (2-7) sign on gate of Bearcat pool (closed for repairs) (8) Belli leaving chopper at Bearcat (9-11) Belli standing outside Bearcat officers club, which was used as courtroom in Lyon case during the first half day, changed at noon recess because of two generators going full blast a few feet outside the window. Don't know the photog, though it may be Danny Jones, but Belli is talking to AF Lt Col Jack C. Dixon, of MacV SJA. (12) Belli and Dixon (13) Dixon and Belli returning from latrine (14) ditto but closer (15-17) Belli and banana tree (18-20) Lt Col James A. Theros, left, president of court trying Lyon, Belli and Dixon. (21) Belli, Theros and Dixon.
- Contact Sheet 14048, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Vietnam crimes - Melvin Belli (C) - Lt. Col. James A. Theros - Danny Jones - Pfc. Roger B. Lyon (murder) - Lt. Col. James A. Hagan - Capt. Charles Rowe (Dr.).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Sheet "C" - for Belli stories & Lyon trial (3) Theros and Belli (4-7) ditto (also Lyon court martial) (8-9) ditto (Belli and Theros) (10) Danny Jones (11) Theros and Belli (12) Pfc Roger D. Lyon (being tried on article 118), Theros scratching his head in back of Lyon, Belli and Lt Col James A. Hagan (wearing shoulder holster .45, we call him the Fastest Overruled in the Far East, also Judge Roy Hagan, Law West of the Pacific, but don't use this), law officer for Lyon general court, outside officers club. (13) Lyon going to lunch. He is in jeep back seat right, Guy in front seat right is giving me a dirty look and possible what the UCMJ calls a contemptuous gesture... (14) Doctor Belli (as Dixon introduced him) at A Co, 9th Med Bln Bearcat hospital (15-18) out of focus (or I moved) but Capt Charles Rowe, M.D., acting CO of A Co, 9th Med Bln, with Belli. (19) still jiggling, through that's Danny Jones in front (20) Rowe, forground, shows Belli hospital equipment (21) Belli and Rowe looking at polaroid X-rays.
- Contact Sheet 14049, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Melvin Belli (D) in hospital - Capt. (Dr.) Charles Rowe - Danny Jones.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Belli captions - 4 - sheet "D" - (1) forget it (think it’s a homemade delivery table) (2-4) Belli and Rowe in surgery (5) "Who needs cholera shots? If my stomach could take that meal I had last night at Cheap Charlie's, nothing as small as a germ is going to bother it--or if it does, a shot or two of Bourbon will take care of anything." Belli is about to get cholera shot. (6-7) Danny Jones gets cholera shot from Speedy 4 Mel McQueen Glass, 20, of Pensicola, Fla. (8) Belli learns about the malaria pills. (9-11) Belli gets cholera shot from Glass (12) Belli leaving the general's mess (13) in the general's jeep, left to right, Speedy 4 Greg Campbell, 21, Alton, Ill., the driver for Roseborough, Danny Jones, Belli, and Brig Gen M. G. Roseborough, asst 9th Div. CO (14-16) ditto as far as where they are sitting. (17) Belli, forground, looking at 155mm howitzer & crew (18) Roseborough, Belli and Jones and Thar she goes! (19) same and waiting for the dust to settle (20-21) in the arty plotting center.
- Contact Sheet 14050, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Melvin Belli (E) - court martial Lyon - Capt. Herb Cohen - Capt. Bill Rittenhouse (Def).